http://youtu.be/47E_7XvvDpo
http://youtu.be/47E_7XvvDpo
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: Throughout this course,
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: Qua khoá học này,
we will present to you a series of short videos on how to read the data sheet.
tôi sẽ cho bạn 1 loạt video ngắn chỉ cách đọc data sheet.
Because this class deals with input and output, in this first video,
Bởi vì lớp này chủ yếu xử lý input và output, trong video đầu tiên này,
we'll show you how to look up IO pins.
tôi cho bạn thấy cách tìm IO pins.
One of the convenient ways to search the data sheet
1 cách tiện lợi cho mỗi data sheet
is to use the table of contents.
là xài mục lục.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: So let's go to Chapter 10, which
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: Hãy coi chương 10,
has information about the general purpose IO pins.
có thông tin của IO pin dùng chung.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: All right, so I'm going to click right here.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: được rồi, tôi sẽ click ở đây.
And now we're in Chapter 10.
và giờ ta đã tới chương 10.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: So what we find here in this page
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: Ta thấy ở trang này
is the description of the fact that they are 43 GPIO pins on our microcontroller
nói là ta có 43 GPIO pin trên con vi điều khiển
and they're called ports.
và được xếp thành port.
And there's port A, B, C, D, E, and F.
là port A, B, C, D, E, và F.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: So one of the questions we might ask
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: 1 câu nên hỏi
is, what's a pin?
1 pin là gì?
So we go back to the table of contents and look for information on pins.
Ta nên trở lại mục lục và tìm thông tin của pin.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: And we'll find it in Chapter 22.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: ta sẽ thấy ở chương 22.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: There it is, Chapter 22.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: vâng, chương 22.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: It should have the pin diagram.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: Nó thường sẽ có giản đồ pin
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: So we click on that.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: nên click vào đó.
All right, so here in Chapter 22, we see the pin diagram.
Đây rồi, chương 22, ta thấy giản đồ pin.
And here's a picture of our microcontroller.
Và đây là hình chụp của con vi điều khiển.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: And so we can identify the pins here.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: và ta thấy pin ở đây.
And in one of our first labs, we have these pins,
trong lab đầu tiên, ta có những pin này,
PF 1, 2, and 3 are going to be outputs.
PF 1, 2, và 3 là những output.
And PF 0 and PF 4 are going to be inputs.
Và PF 0 và PF 4 là những input.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: So the answer to the question
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: vậy câu trả lời là
is, a pin is an actual signal connected to the microcontroller with which we
1 pin là 1 tín hiệu kết nối từ vi điều khiển với
are going to do our input and output.
những thứ mà ta sẽ làm input và output.
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: And this is the actual, physical layout
DR. RAMESH YERRABALLI: và đây là layout
at the chip level.
của chip.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: Yup.
DR. JONATHAN VALVANO: vâng.